If you're not comfortable, that's where
you have to be. Like, if you are too
comfortable, you're not sizing in
properly, you know?
You have to be very, very uncomfortable
because that's where growth growth comes
comes from. That's correct.
>> And whenever like I don't know if you
have experienced this, but I think
probably the like the differentiated
factor of the best traders out there is
risk tolerance. And how do you work on
risk tolerance?
That's only by
Markets, speculation, [music] and risk.
This is the Chat With Traders podcast.
Welcome back to Chat With Traders. If
you've been listening to this show for a
while, you know it's become one of the
most respected platforms in the trading
world for thoughtful, honest
conversations with traders from all
walks of the markets. Well, before we
get started, I I wanted to take a moment
to recognize the people who built this
incredible foundation. Chat With Traders
began with Aaron Fifield, whose
curiosity and passion for the markets
helped create something truly special.
Over the years, the show continued to
grow thanks to Tessa and Ian Cox, who
each carried the torch forward and
continued the tradition of bringing
meaningful conversations with traders to
this audience. My name's Kevin Avery,
you may not recognize the voice, and I'm
incredibly honored to be stepping in as
the new host of Chat With Traders. Like
many of you, I've spent years fascinated
by the markets, not just the charts and
the trades, but really the people behind
them and the journeys they've taken to
get where they are. Throughout my
journey, my mission's really always been
very simple, it's just I want to add as
much value as I can to the trader. And
that's why this role feels so meaningful
to me because Chat With Traders has
always been about that, and sharing real
experiences, real lessons, real insight
that can help traders grow and improve.
What makes trading so compelling is that
no two paths look the same. Every trader
develops their own philosophy, their own
edge, and their own way of navigating
uncertainty. My goal as host is to
continue the legacy of this show by
bringing you insightful conversations
with traders who are willing to share
the real story. That means successes,
that means failures, struggles, lessons
learned, and the mindset it takes to
survive and thrive in the markets. So,
whether you're a season trader or just
beginning your journey, I hope these
conversations give you ideas,
perspective, and maybe even a few
lessons you can apply to your own
trading. So, with that, traders, let's
get into today's conversation, episode
321. All right, traders, welcome to
another episode of Chat with Traders.
We're here today with Eduardo, otherwise
known as Edu Trades. He started, guys,
with just $1,900,
and Eduardo's grown that account now to
more than 2.9
million trading small caps.
What makes his journey even more
compelling is his results are fully
audited and verifiable through Kinfo.
I've actually known Eduardo since 2018
and have had the chance to just watch
his trajectory over the years as he's
developed into the trader that he is
today.
He reached out to me a video I did way
back when and asked if he could share
that with his students, and he shared
with me recently he just consumed all
kinds of content, just consumed it over
all the years.
He brings a strong academic background
to his trading. He has a background in
electrical engineering, and then he
later earned an MBA in finance. So,
combining technical thinking with a deep
understanding of the markets.
That same year, in 2018, he founded
Stocks Trading Club, which has grown
into the largest Spanish-speaking
community focused on small-cap trading.
He's helped thousands and thousands of
traders learn the markets in their
native language.
Eduardo's journey is a powerful example
of what's possible through resilience,
discipline, and staying committed to the
process. And that's what I've seen, too,
as well. EduTrades is grit and
determination. That's what I've seen
that elevates traders to their next
level. So, with that said, traders, I'm
excited to welcome EduTrades. Edu,
welcome to Chat With Traders. Thank you
so much for joining. How are you? Kevin,
how are you? This is
uh very exciting for me because when I
started uh Chat With Traders was one of
the most contents that I consume a lot,
and it's quite an honor to be here and
with this beautiful audience that I know
that
um you guys are eager to learn some
trading. So, let's see if I can, you
know, uh give a little bit of that. Oh,
you'll you'll add so much value. And
you're right, this is the best audience.
It's been around for now 10 years.
Um and we're going to continue that
momentum forward. So, take us back to
the beginning. Growing up in Venezuela
and eventually finding trading. I'm so
curious to hear like what initially
pulled you to the markets and what I
mean, what were you doing at that time?
Were you studying in the university,
getting your engineer degree? Take us
back. Man, I think I think um
Hollywood was the one that got me into
trading just because we saw we see a lot
of movies and stuff regarding
uh you know, like Wolf of Wall Street
and all these movies that
uh
in a way alerts us to go into the
markets. So, I was um actually I was
studying engineering and I wanted to
do something, you know, related to the
stock market or something like that. So,
I I tried to
um once I got the engineering degree to
get into this Casa de Bolsa in in which
are
uh
like shops in in in Venezuela. But right
when I was going to Chavez, which was
the the former president there, he
seized all the uh
exchanges in all the shops in within
Venezuela. So,
you know, it got delayed like 2 years or
something like that, and I started
wandering, and and I
I did the MBA in finance just because I
thought it was going to
in a way put me in that scope, you know,
into something related to the stock
market. What I realized is that the MBA
what gives you is in a way
uh
you know, manage funds that are very
very big for very very big people or
working for banks or something like
that, you know, and I that's not what I
wanted to do. So, a a teacher, a
professor in the university suggested me
to do a trading and investment course,
and that's what I started to see
volatility, see liquidity, see all these
assets, which were back then like
futures, forex, and all these things.
And what I realized is, okay, this is
something that I this is what I want to
do, but
you know, futures and forex uh it
doesn't give me a lot of edge. I don't I
don't really understand it. So, I
started to understand that volatility
and liquidity was the one that I was
looking for and as a day trader, you
know. And
I just typed which were the the the most
volatile assets back then, and it was
penny stocks. And of course, back then
the father of the penny stocks was Tim
Sykes, who was all over the place with
all this advertising and you know, his
um orange Lambo and all those things.
So, I started to to uh um
you know learn from him the Penny Stock
framework which is
till this day
almost 11 years ago till this day
the fundamentals of what I do basically.
So at what point did you say you know
what I'm I'm moving to the States and
leaving Venezuela? At what what point in
time was that? Well, political situation
in Venezuela was crazy bad.
This was by the end of 2017
I think.
We decided hey, let's let's go and study
in the States and do something different
because this is going to be crazy and
that's why we we moved to the States.
My wife was a studying
and I you know I was like you know what
don't worry cuz I've been trading and I
I found out I figured out and I was
making a little money but I don't know
if you guys have done this but
if you find some success in trading
you'll be like oh so
this is how I made I don't know 1,000
bucks. So maybe if I increase my size by
10 now I can make 10,000. And that's how
I you know I was like don't worry baby
we're going to be fine cuz I'm going to
be you know living out of trading and
that was probably the worst decision
that I've that I've made so far because
really you're trying to you know survive
trading you know. Is that because it now
turned into what they call sacred money
and this is money like you need to
survive with and that kind of those
emotions
kind of change your trading don't they
cuz now you're less trading the chart
and more trading cuz hey I got to buy
groceries at the end of the 100% back
then
I was trading probably like rent money
and diaper money cuz my my daughter just
she was just born at that time.
So I was like, yeah,
I'm I'm trading. I need
I don't know, $2,000, $3,000 a month to
to complete my expenses, my my monthly
expenses. And I was so focused on
surviving by that time that I screw up
like I I lost a lot of money. Like I I I
probably when you say at first when you
said at first that I started with
$1,900.
That's true, but I
I probably blew up like three or four
accounts. Okay. Of that more or less of
that
quantity like probably 2,000 or 3,000
bucks like three or four accounts. So
did you find your success after moving
to the states where those few accounts
in the transition from Venezuela now to
the US? And then how many years do you
think it it was until you took an
account I started to to be consistent
cuz you obviously I had some success
regarding being profitable. The thing is
I had for example a $2,000 account and I
had a $1,000 a month.
Those $3,000
on my my equity, I withdraw a thousand
for example. And I started again with
2,000. So yes, I could be I don't know,
$5,000 up on the year, but
if I lost 2,000, I blew up my account.
Okay, I I have a very interesting
question regarding that because some
traders I've talked to and obviously I
mean we've know how that you've grown
this substantially. So what do you say
to the traders? There are some I've
heard that say, "Look, it's helpful for
me if my back's against the wall. Like I
don't want cushion because when you
introduce cushion, you introduce more
risk in the and so you allow for let's
say more flexibility on certain trades.
What do you say like some traders like
their backs against the wall. They say,
oh, I if I have 10,000 extra in my
account, I'm going to give more risk to
this trade. So what do you say to those
traders that you know, should should you
just slowly just slowly size up because
you said
you made a thousand dollars and now you
thought, oh, I can make 10,000. Let's
just add some zeros. Let's add zeros to
the end of the order.
What separates that trader? What's the
balance there? Do you you understand
that question? What's the balance there
between now I can size yeah. Sizing up,
I think it's one of the hardest thing to
do as as you're finding success as a
trader is sizing up.
For me back then, it was not about about
sizing. It
was about surviving and I think that's
what what make it so much harder. Um but
in a way
what give me that um let's see it say
peace of mind in order to to start
trading was having alternatives. And
what do I mean about about that? For me
at first was having that, you know,
between the sword and the and the wall.
You know, having that
plan B's plan A kind of thing. But then
and and and because of that made me very
very eager to consume content to you
know, to uh
work on myself a lot to um
have the journaling thing, you know,
work a lot in my trading skills. But
once I had the
the other alternative to do something
else Mhm. I I had so much peace of mind
in order to really apply trading as a
skill and as a profession rather than a
the last chance that I had.
That and that
uh it was I remember the exact moment
that it was and was when I got my green
card. Like when I got my green it was
like oh, so I can do other things. Like
I can I'm an engineer, so I maybe can
find something else, find another, let's
say, uh source of income, so I can, you
know, support my family and provide for
my family. So, that was exactly, and
this is this is very very is it was such
a coincidence because it was right
before the pandemic hit.
And this was on 2020,
uh which I had already maybe 4 years
already in into the game. I was already
uh profitable back then, but it was
little money. Like it was not money that
I could that that it could change my
life.
But once the pandemic hit,
market went crazy, market went insane.
And that's why
I said I always said I was lucky. Uh
lucky for me is when preparation meets
opportunity, and that opportunity was
huge, like it was incredible. You had
400% runners every single day, maybe
four or five,
four probably like
16 months straight.
You had this crazy crazy opportunity, um
and I was prepared, I was like I had the
skill already. I
had this confidence in my skills, and I
had this
alternative in a way. So, if this
doesn't work, like I'm not going to be,
s- you know, my my family's not going to
be you know, starving.
>> Yeah. That's That's amazing. It sounds
like it gave you the freedom to now just
jump. The freedom to jump. So, let's uh
I wouldn't call it freedom, Kevin, cuz
I didn't have the job. I didn't have the
source of income, but my mindset was
on the chart. It was not on the money by
then, you know what I'm saying?
>> Yeah. Yeah. You try It sounds like you
had you have this capability. You trust
yourself. Worst comes to worst, you get
that job, you know?
Um
Exactly. That was like my my last
alternative. Like plan B was not
trading, and that was such a relief. And
now I could really apply the plan A, you
know? Yeah. That's amazing. So, let's
rewind a little bit and talk about the
evolution of this strategy for the
traders that may not know. Have you
stayed consistent in your approach and
what you've been trading? Are Are you Do
you more long bias, short bias, what
Wait, obviously, uh
as as you grow, as you
have that evolution as any trader should
have, of course you do a lot of things
differently. Like now, I I manage a
much bigger account back that than back
then.
Uh we're in a really really different
market cycle that we than we used to. Um
it seems like 2026 seems a lot like 2022
just because as we had as we were
preceded by a really hot market, which
was 2020, 2021, and 2025 for 2026.
Um I think it's really really alike that
you get this
eager to crush it because you know the
market is there, and then you push the
gas, and then the market is not there.
So, you
You know, I've been
um struggling, not struggling because it
it I've been profitable past 3 months,
but it's not the same than 2025. So,
that's why I I still looks alike 2025.
It shows your trader the the level of
your trader maturity though. I say it
like this
at EduTrades where it's traders want to
go 75 in like a school zone in a 35
[clears throat]
and and we're in a school zone. You
know, those sometime the market right it
ebbs and flows.
>> Such a good analogy actually. Yeah.
Yeah, use it. Use it. You said
I'll I'll take a I'll take some
royalties.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, it's
it's true cuz
>> Yeah. I remember I was in in a Traders
for a Cause event. I think it was 2022
or 2021 or I don't remember.
And Scott Manso, which is a a
well,
a veteran trader and he explained how
you can you have to adapt cycles by
being defensive or by being in
defensive. Okay.
We were in a in a market which you had
to be in the defensive
position, you know, I think nowadays I
think
you have so much more opportunity than
than when I started. Like you have these
crazy runners. For example, we we had
today WNW, which was a Chinese stock
that went from two to 13 then to 13 to
two. Like that's volatility and that's
what we like, but it's so so much range
that
you know, being defensive because it's a
slow market and I would put it as a, you
know, as quote unquote Yeah, yeah. cuz
it's not. Like if you see the
the gappers in 2022, I posted a
in Twitter on X.
Look like a boomer now saying Twitter,
but whatever.
On X I put um I posted a
a tweet which was
comparing 2022 and 2026 markets. And you
can see that in 2022, we had
by that time, I think it was middle of
of February, it was like probably like
17 gappers more than 50% and in 2026, we
had already
uh 77 or something like that. And the
average gap was like 61% in 2022 and
2026 was 118%
Wow. Obviously, you get that feeling
that the market is slower just because
you had a crazy 2025. Like 2025
I I made 10x of my money. You know, and
Yeah. And it was a
decent account, so it was crazy. It was
crazy market. Now
>> And I
I've heard you say too on a separate
podcast those you had a significant
amount of gappers and then you mentioned
on that podcast how you were able to
actually look look historically at the
gappers and what they were doing and a
high percentage of them were closing red
on the day. I'm sure that accounted for
some of your strategy which I wanted to
get into next which is
the triad trading is what I've heard you
call it. It's a triangle of strategy,
risk management, and mindset. I'm
curious if you can break those elements
down maybe starting with strategy.
Yeah, sure. So, for me a strategy would
be the base of the triangle. Just
picture a triangle and the base which is
the most important part would be a
strategy. Um what strategy?
On strategy, what I mean by that is
you have to have an edge on the market.
You have to have an advantage. You have
to have a statistical advantage in your
favor in order to
um
benefit from the movement of the market
of the from the moves of the market. No.
So, for me, uh this is strategy is based
on the penny stock framework and the
statistics of those penny stocks. What
What I What I mean by penny stocks is is
stocks that are below, um maybe 1
billion market cap. Okay. Um
I usually like my bread and butter would
be below even 200 million uh dollar
market cap. So, there are small gaps.
Like they're they're very very volatile
stocks,
uh which
they usually are very very bad
companies. And why Why we say bad
companies is because they make money.
And if you see the fundamentals of them,
um most of them, and I would say like
90% of them, um
they
uh
like they lack of good financials. They
lack of good fundamentals. And because
they [clears throat] they don't sell
anything. Like they they are in the
middle of maybe finding this patent or
or maybe in the middle of getting that
FDA approval. Or they have this crazy
expectative of, you know, having this
drone that will make the market go fire
or whatever, you know. And um
what these companies do as they are very
very bad companies, they have to finance
themselves with
Offerings. You know, out of the stock
Right. How do you say that? Out of the
the stock uh owner. You know, I don't
know how to say stockholder. That's the
That's the word that I was looking for
in English. [clears throat] So,
because of that, they have to hype up
the price in a way, you know, with a
press release or whatever.
And then they have, you know, usually
they have toxic financing in order to
raise that money so they can still keep
operating with, you know, having nothing
to sell. So, this is a
this is something that I've seen since I
started and the videos of the people
that taught me, which was Tim, Nate, all
these guys,
what I what I've saw is what I've seen
is that it's the same
um protocol over and over with a little
bit of tweak. Like when I started, that
hype was over, for example, um
those emails that pump the stock.
Right.
And right now we have groups,
uh
Slack rules, Discord, or whatever that
really pump up the stock. So,
if you see the the mechanism would
change, but the fundamentals of it Yeah,
but the greed and the FOMO is there.
Paired with what you mentioned
paired with the companies that are in
terrible financial situation and that
creates an edge. That creates an edge.
>> so and that edge, um it's called well,
the penny stock framework, which is a
Tim Sykes concept. Uh it's very
interesting because what it makes is
this, you know, crazy run-up, then you
have that crazy, um
fall of prices, maybe 50% of of of of,
you know, of discount. Then you have
those bounces, those crazy bounces, and
then you have like if you drop a a ball
from, you know,
a building or whatever, you know, first
you got this crazy bounce and then you
got like bounces and then it dies. You
know, that kind of framework what I what
my strategy is focused on is to
understanding which stage of that
framework I am so I can be, for example,
in the first stage of the framework, I
would be a long basis penetrator, you
know? But, they usually, as you said,
that statistically, when you see every
single small cap that has been
doing a gap over 20%,
which is that 20% is against the
previous close. So, if you see what
every single one of them do is they
usually
77%
of them or 76% of them
um
they close red in the day. Usually, they
close red 8% below the close on average.
And what is very, very interesting is
that how they do it because they
usually, on the first 25 minutes, they
uh do a spike, you know? Uh on average,
they do like 20% spike or something like
that.
And at 10 at 9:50 a.m., they reach their
peak.
And they usually, you know, fade
all day. That's That's how That's the
behavior of most gappers. But, there's
something really, really interesting,
Kevin, because
uh you would say, "Oh, so let's short
everything that gaps up." Right?
But, what happens is that 25% of them
they could run like crazy. They could
run 100%, 200%, 300%. And that's why you
have to be really, really careful
because if you don't
uh you could probably lose your account
in one of these crazy things.
And what is very, very interesting is
within that 25%
the high of day is not made at 9:50
a.m., it's made at noon.
So, you could say, in very few
conclusions and very very quick
conclusions is if you see a stock that
is making new highs at noon, don't short
it.
You know, stuff like that. And and
that's how I develop this system where I
understanding which part of this state
in which stage of my pattern I am and
whether I'm going long in that pattern
whether that I'm going short. That's
probably it. That's strategy.
Okay.
So so you you may work both sides of it.
You may take the long and short of it.
Is that what I'm hearing? Actually I'm
40%
long and 60% short.
>> Okay.
But my longs made more money than my
shorts. Like I I would say that my
shorts are the cash flow of the business
if we're looking at trading as a
business and the longs will probably be
my growth of the business, let's say.
And and this is all small caps? This is
all small caps, yeah. Like I I don't
trade anything. Well, maybe like
as as we had this crazy
uh for example
um this year we had the silver madness.
>> Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. I have never
traded anything that is not small caps.
Maybe a mid cap now and then, but like
99% it's small caps and I traded even
silver and oil. Of course I I traded
those
uh with ETFs and stuff. Because that
same euphoria and greed human behavior
was there?
>> that they were behaving like penny
stocks. Yeah, right, right, [laughter]
yeah, exactly.
>> Like those those run up 100% run up in a
in probably like 3 months or something.
Like that's something that you have to
notice and that's something of that
evolution as a trader that you will find
that maybe you can be really narrow down
to trade one asset and then you find out
a lot of things because I've seen a lot
of things and
you know, I adapt because in this year
like small cap I I've been like
probably like
13% up this year.
But
it's something that I'm not used to
maybe maybe
cuz I trade with really really small
accounts at first. This is the first
year that I'm trading with a with a
large account in compared to my other
years. So for me it was very very
unusual to to only be 10% and I started
seeing other opportunities because in
small caps
you don't have the crazy market that we
What have the emotions been like for you
as you've scaled so much? It have they
played a part because there's a
there's a third part to this triangle
which is mindset and I I'm huge on the
trader psychology myself.
I love the Mark Douglas books for
example. So the mindset and and sizing
up that you have done over the years it
have how have you managed the emotions
of that? Are you able to still just
focus on
good trading?
Well, remember that the other part of
the So the base of the triangle would be
the strategy the edge. The other side
would be risk management and
sizing which is for me like if you don't
have
position
risk management especially in this small
caps that are really
volatile that
you you could have the all the mindset
that you want but you're screwed, you
know? So
this part which is managing emotions, I
think it's probably
I see a lot of traders focusing on this
the first stage of their careers
and I think that's a mistake because
what you have to really dip into or dive
into in the first years would be the
strategy and the position sizing and
risk management, you know, the technical
stuff. Yeah. You have to really master
the these two things because if you dive
in into the mindset thing,
I mean, you will be blaming your mindset
every single time because you don't know
if you have an edge still. So, you will
be blaming every single time, "Oh, I
have a conflict of interest because I
I don't know. I
To me, when I was growing up,
being rich was for thieves. I don't
know, like, whatever. And I'm not a th-
a thief, so um I have a conflict of
interest in my mindset, you know."
>> So, what I would suggest every single
time is dive into the technical part of
the first 2 years. Like, that edge, you
have to understand what your edge is.
And
understand how you can, you know, have a
a proper risk management and how to size
up and have this, you know, position
sizing in a proper way, applying in a
proper way. And then, of course, for me,
for example, right now,
mindset is my thing. Like, mindset is
whatever is holding me back to not be a
better trader would be mindset. But see,
I'm I'm
>> [clears throat]
>> in a stage of my career that I already
know where my edge is. I already know
what what I'm good at. I already know
how to adapt to the markets. I already
know how to, you know, be careful in
this, be really defensive in this, or be
very aggressive in this. Like, I already
know what what to do.
Okay.
>> But is my mindset what keeps me uh away
from being a $10 million trader and
rather I'm, you know, a a seven figure
trader, but what about the 10 figures
now?
You know, the mindset for me would be
not only manage your emotions, but being
what you're capable of.
And that for me is is the struggle right
now.
Um okay, how can I
um
understand for example, I'm a I'm a very
very
um
winning percentage rate kind of trader.
How can I now as you scale?
Um being a a winning percentage trader
is not the best to scale if you if
you're going to really scale. You have
to be more risk reward oriented and that
means that you're going to lose more
times. So, how can your mindset can
absorb that kind of new identity and
understand that it's okay to have a red
months for example. Like for me, that
would be
the the thing about mindset for now. Of
course, controlling your emotions
because when you're in a drawdown for
example, um you tend to question
yourself a lot.
I
haven't met a trader that doesn't
question himself.
Uh I've
known I've met amazing incredible
traders and they have the same thing,
but in another level, but they have the
same
uh this
oh, maybe the I lost my edge. Maybe this
market is the one that I'm not going to
make money from. Maybe you know, and you
start questioning yourself. I think
mindset is the one that takes uh
you know, control over that pyramid or
or over that triangle
in those stages. And when you're doing
well,
the mindset would be the one that
commands this confidence and this, you
know, I got this.
And whenever you're confident, of
course, you tend to size up more.
And when you size up more, of course,
you're going to have this crazy
drawdown. So, it's this
it's like a cycle and it's And And this
cycle, what is very very And what I love
about trading is that you have to grow.
Otherwise, you You have to grow in order
to stay the same.
And you have to grow times two in order
to grow your equity curve. You know, so
if you stay where you are,
you're going to lose money.
Cuz you have to adapt to the markets.
And this is like such a
um
an elite kind of
um let's say profession that
that's why you have to keep
um
adding to your knowledge account, to
your
uh experience account, to your stress
account. You don't want to add on there.
Like you have to be really, really aware
that you have also um
a stress account where you don't um
nobody takes it into consideration until
they're in a in an in the edge of the
burnout. You know? So, it's very, very
important to to understand all these
things and to understand that this is a
marathon. I think people are very, very
eager to to earn money and they
um
they
totally forget about the journey and
what it implies. And once you get there,
okay, yeah, you made money already. I've
seen so many really good traders burn
out and they don't want to know anything
about day trading. They They start swing
trading, they're starting investment
because they they made it. Like
obviously, it's a very, very like for a
successful trader, um
this is a very, very nice
um source of of income, of course.
But you get that burnout.
[clears throat]
So you have to, you know, balance all
these things. You have to balance them
and and you know,
um
adapt them to your personality way.
This is incredible. I got to remember
I'm interviewing you here cuz I'm just
listening and this is like like a viewer
here. I mean, this is incredible. They
There's a lot to
digest there. I mean, you There's so
much wisdom. A couple things.
One you pointed out, you know when to
size on certain plays. I like this
analogy where I've used where this this
is like we're playing poker and maybe
this hands a pocket ace, this hands a
pocket 10. So but over the years, and
would you agree with this? Experience
really is your best teacher as far as
that goes. Like you you have to identify
your edge as you said, but then do you
think there's multiple edges out there
that may have Yeah, that may may
deserve, let's say, more risk. Like I'm
sizing up on on this setup versus the
next. And every time I meet another
trader, and I've met a lot,
I I'm more impressed
by the
amount multiple possibilities that there
is to make money in the markets. Like
I haven't seen
one that makes the same exactly the same
than the other. And that's why I think,
obviously, you have to have this edge
where it fits your personality. And I
think every trader has this his own or
her own way of doing things.
And I think it's That's where the art
part comes in. You know, that's where
the Okay, how how can I make this
happen? How can I profit from this edge?
Which is, okay, you have this edge of, I
don't know, whatever.
I've seen a lot of traders doing mid-cap
swings, for example. But I've seen a lot
of traders doing large caps. I've seen a
lot of traders in small caps. I've seen
a lot of traders in futures.
I haven't seen a lot of forex, though.
Um I haven't met like day traders in
forex. I haven't met
quite successful traders in forex. And
and I believe it's because of how
efficient forex market is.
Um but in all this, and and I'm sure
there is an edge in forex, of course.
So, what I'm trying to say is it doesn't
matter where you find your edge. What
matters is how you explode it. You know,
explode explode it. Um and what that
means is if you have
something that you know it could happen,
and this is a concept that Lance Breunig
brings it in, which is the EV
the expectancy.
>> Expected value, yeah. So,
expected value, exactly. So, how can I
know First, I I think edge is knowing
where that EV comes from. Mhm.
And obviously having that positive EV,
right? But what it makes
a really successful trader is how you
exploit that with size.
And that's where it it gets very very,
let's say, I
I don't want to say hard, but that's
where the trick comes from. You know,
how do I know that this set up
is the one that I'm going to be sized
in. How can I know that I'm in the
market cycle where that set up uh have
better EV, for example, so so my size
[clears throat] and my risk is going to
be aligned with that positive EV, you
know? So, I think that's probably the
the most difficult part, I think,
because
yeah, you're going to know that that's
the play that you're going to you're
going to size in. That's you know for a
fact that that's where you want to put
your risk on.
But, when you're going to press that
button you're going to click click that.
Yeah. It gets so many different things
along the way that experience is the one
that will remove that. Yes.
>> Experience is probably
And that's why I love what you said,
because experience
it that's why a new trader
it's very very hard to teach this
confidence, because that confidence come
from from not only technical stuff and
and journaling a lot and understanding
what's your edge, but experience.
And experience is what gives you that,
"Hey, I've seen this I don't know
15 50 times.
And I know this behaves like this.
And
I'm confident enough to lose money. So,
you're saying even if you're not even
comfortable with doing it,
you still do it because you've seen it
so many Yeah, yeah, that's where you you
get elevated to the next level. And
honestly, If you're not comfortable,
that's where where you have to be. Like,
if you're too comfortable, you're not
sizing in properly, you know?
You have to be very very uncomfortable,
because that's where growth growth comes
comes from. That's great. And whenever
like I don't know if you have
experienced this, but I think probably
the like the differentiated factor of
the best traders out there is risk
tolerance. And how do you
work on risk tolerance?
That's only by putting size. Like, you
cannot work on risk tolerance and and I
really believe that we all have natural
risk tolerance, like you have uh let's
say uh
uh
How do you say that? Like an umbral,
which is I'm sorry. I'm trying to
translate in my in my in my head. But
it's just like a a threshold. That's the
word that I was looking for. You have a
threshold of pain, let's say.
And you have this natural um
risk tolerance,
which you're going to work on and you're
going to
hit that limit. But once you get to that
limit,
you can't go further. And that's That's
how what what I've seen in in a lot of
traders that I've that I've met is that
there are people that have the risk
tolerance like crazy high. Yeah. And
they're very very far from their
let's say limit.
Um me, for example, I I know that I have
this limit,
but I know that it I'm really really far
from it.
From Okay. And I've seen traders that
they have been trading for
30 years,
and they told me and they haven't traded
the last 10
because they
crashed into that threshold or crashed
into that limit where they go like you
know what? This is This is excellent. I
mean, such good advice. Just getting
outside that comfort zone that we're in
to push, you know, against that that
threshold. Couple things here. So, first
of all,
what do you say to the trader that let's
say they put on that size on a trade,
but now they find themselves fearful,
and they're watching every tick, every
movement, and now they're taking profits
too early. So, it almost works against
them. They sized up, but now they're so
nervous. What do you say to that trader?
I would say it's okay to do that. Like
once that trade ends, you will find in
in your journal that you shouldn't have.
And next time
you have to follow your plan. Like for
example, for me
I I I make a process and this process is
first, you got to do your watch list,
right? It's your your due diligence to
the markets and you're going to
understand where your edge is and if
what you're seeing in the markets adapts
to what you know your edge is.
Then, after you have all this data
you will have to do this checklist,
let's say, which is I call it studying
the case. And that studying the case
would be, okay, now that you have that
information, you will be
okay. Where is the best
the best entry for this setup? Where
how can I apply the risk management? How
can I size up?
Is this catalyst
aligns with my theory of this setup?
Does it have dilution, for example, this
stock? You know, it's all this like
checklist. And once you do that
you execute, right? When you execute,
that's the third part of the of the
process. When you execute, you become a
robot. You know, cuz you you you already
planned this on this first two stages or
this first two steps.
On the third one, you have to be a
robot. If you are not
there's the fourth step that would be
the journaling, which is for me is
report cards.
SMB Capital uses a lot. You use a use it
a lot. Um
and it's it's right of
Dr. Brain Stine
um
Brain Stine
Brain Stine his last name, but the daily
trading coach, the author of The Daily
Trading Coach. Yes. So,
that's where I got the the report card
thing. What that journaling will make
you is
understand if your
um performance
uh understand your performance in point
basis, let's say. Because
so many people take into consideration
the money that they make on the trade,
so they can judge it
that they are not taking into account
the
the actual performance in the trade. So,
when you do that process of four steps
and
on a weekly basis you start gathering
data, which is a statistical data. So,
the report card would be something like
uh the quan- the quality the quality
side of the of the trade to analyze the
quality side, but the data will give you
the quantity side of the trade. So, when
when once you do that
and once you understand
uh what you're good at and what you can
improve, you will see
that you're taking profits very soon.
So, your job as a trader is to try to
uh okay, I'm taking profits too soon.
Okay.
How can I do that? I'm too anxious, I'm
too whatever. Okay, let's do something.
Instead of taking the whole position,
I'm going to take 10% instead of I don't
know, 75% or or all of the position. I'm
going to take 10% because my journal
says and my data says that I
can improve if I don't take profits too
soon. Yeah. And that's why I'm taking
10% for example. Sometimes what happens
is the trade goes against you.
And
that's something that you will find in
your data, too. Like, you can find if
the market that you're in
sometimes it goes against you every
single time. So, you have to be adapting
every single time, and that's why I say
that you always have to be,
you know, considering
on growing and working on yourself every
single
day and every single week just because
of those things. Like, you have to
um
take advantage of the market you're in
and remember that history repeat itself
it doesn't repeat itself, but it rhymes.
So, maybe what you've you have seen in
2020 and 2021 will not be the same in
2025, but you have seen something really
really really similar. So, that's
>> you're going to take advantage of it and
by tweaking that journaling phase
is how you will become better.
>> Mhm.
Yeah, I want to I want to speak on the
the the 25% of time you mentioned
earlier where we get these black swan
events because like you just said,
history rhymes. I mean, we saw one
today, not to date the video, but we had
a crazy mover today, and then we but
we've had those over and over. I'm
thinking of so many. DRYS, HMNY, TCGL,
QMM and just the list goes on. So, how
do you
with the risk management and how you
size? I'm curious about your sizing as
well, whether you're single entries,
multiple exits or multiple entries and
exits, but is there a point in time
where you can recognize, "Okay, this is
a an a this is a ticker I need to avoid.
I'm going to just shut the computer
down, not look at it, or only give it
like one or two tries."
Can you expand upon that? 100%. I I use
fundamentals for conviction. Like, my
trading is 75% price action, I would
say. Okay. But there's this 25%
it it it doesn't mean that it's
irrelevant,
but it really gives me conviction. For
example, today on WNW,
which is a Chinese stock,
I have seen so many Chinese stocks doing
this
that
you know,
for me it's an avoid on the long side.
Like for me, I was just looking for that
backside, and I was just waiting for it
to go to VWAP and to bounce off VWAP to
to short it.
And that's when it went from 13 to
seven-ish, I think. And then that
bounced to the eighth, that's where I
got it. But
it's it's it's funny because if you see
the first stage of that run-up, which
went from two to 13, that's something
that that I would be all over on the
long side. But as it was a Chinese
stock, and as it as it For example, I
see a lot of catalysts, I see a lot of
um
I'm trying to understand dilution, for
example, and all these things.
I tend to avoid a few longs that have
some characteristics.
For example, this one I totally avoided
on the on the Maybe I I had a few longs,
but it wasn't crazy. Where I size in was
on the backside of the of that trade.
And I
I I
as my journal says that I take profits
too soon,
um on this one was quite a fumble
because this one went to the eighth
to three on that bounce, right? To four.
And then it bounced like crazy to the
eighth again, and I
I I got off from the trade.
And then it went all the way to two,
you know, from the eights. So, when you
get in you can have
So, let's just take this for example.
You got in on a VWAP bounce
um from six to eight. The high was 13.
What's how What's your risk management
look like on a trade like that?
On stocks that has so much range,
it like it's very, very harder for me to
to apply the risk management um because
I I let's say I draw a line
on the level of price that I think it's
not going to work that that that short
or that trade. For example, for me was
the 1050 because it was it was a it was
the last time that it that it uh it
bounced off of that level and then when
it crash it, it it it couldn't go back
to that level. So, for me it was a 1050.
So, what I what I do is I try to uh
apply my position sizing
uh over that
risk management, let's say. For example,
if I know I'm going till the 1050s,
uh what I do is I don't size in all of
my
uh all of
>> Okay. You size it towards the 1050. You
size it up up towards that area. But but
if but it try to cut like
that's why I I recycle shares a lot
because I
I divide the trade in levels until that
1050. Like if that 1050
um if if the price goes to that 1050, I
get out from the trade. But if it goes
to the eights, you will see a lot of red
triangles right there, right? But if it
goes to 840 for example, you will see uh
a cover.
Not my whole position, but I cannot be
sized in in the eights until 10:50.
That's crazy cuz that's a 25% range. So,
when I have this really
large range, I split the trade. Let's
say, having that 10:50 as my
ultimate level as my Okay, if it goes
through here, it means that it's not a
short anymore. But, I can scale down or
scale up within that range. You know
what I mean? And then if it cracks back
under VWAP again, can you then size into
that winner? Yes. Okay. That's what
That's what I do. I de-scale a lot
>> Dynamic. whenever it goes against me.
Yeah. And I scale a lot whenever it goes
in my favor. That's That's what I
technically and I my
study would be my technique in a way.
Reducing risk. Reducing risk. Increasing
risk along the way in that area that I
know that it is it is a still a really
good short, for example, or a really
good long. Doesn't matter. So, that
would be my technique in order to apply
that strategy.
That's amazing to hear. I mean,
personally that's explaining it in audio
though.
Yeah, yeah. You're like, we need to pull
up some charts here and explain it. But,
you know, it's hard to explain in audio.
Well, I think that I think the traders
listening are finding immense value. I
mean, I know I am. That's Personally,
that's the struggles really stepping
outside the comfort zone and sizing
winners. And to hear you saying that's
okay, be uncomfortable, and that's
what's really going to take you to that
next level. So, I've heard from you that
you said uh in a prior video that stock
selection is your main strength. So, I
want to narrow in our focus on that.
What do you tell the trader out there
that's
maybe they just don't they don't know
what stock to pick. They're They look at
the leading gapper or maybe they found a
ticker that came out with great news,
but there's no volume there. So, I I
heard you say you're a trader of price
action. What are you looking for when
you're picking your stocks for your
watch list in the morning? Well, first
you remember that we already talked
about how I know
what I'm good at. Yeah.
>> That's why I'm good at stock selection.
It's not that I'm a wizard of on stocks
that I know which one is going to run,
but I know which one I'm good at. I
might miss a lot of opportunities in the
day because I only pick the one that I
know how to treat. You know, so what
what that means is if you have my
background, I can teach you the secret
sauce, but you will have to have my
background and you will have to
understand the trades that I make the
way that I do. So, I would think that
that would be like a a general tip
would be to obviously know what you're
comfortable with.
For example, if you're comfortable with
shorting instead of longing, um
I would look for that second stage of
the pattern.
No not second, it would be like the
fourth the stage of the pattern, but it
would be the backside of the trade. Like
I'm very very
This is This sounds funny in my head
because I was going to say that I'm very
very conservative trader and I trade
small caps that goes from two to 13 and
two 13 to two. So, that that's not true,
but in that madness, I'm a very very
conservative trader.
And I usually um
go short on the backside. So, what I
would tell people is, okay, if you
wanted if you want to short first, you
got to have
extension.
Like if you don't have extension, uh
your chances of of that stock going
against you is is very high. Unless it
has a crazy dilution, for example, like
I've I've shorted stocks, you know, in
the 20% range of gap just because I know
that they have crazy dilution and they
don't have
that much opportunity to
bring liquidity in, so they destroy the
stock the first day. And that could be
an exception, but usually what you have
to
um
look for is extension. And even in the
long side because you would say, "So, I
I in the long side you have to buy cheap
so I can sell, you know, expand in more
expensive, right?"
And or buy low and say high and sell
high. But
for me it's not that. For me
the better the biggest extension,
I would be long in a 1,000% extension.
Why?
Just because I know that there's so many
short sellers there
that I know that they're mistaken and
that I know that they're losing a lot of
money, so I take advantage of that. I
know the
let's say the counterpart of my trade, I
know who is on the other side of that
trade. So,
I will always look for extension even if
it's if I'm longing. Like I'm I'm I'm I
think it's very very important that if
you're in a very slow market, you will
find that there are not enough runners.
Like they you might have like a
40% runner here and here and here and
there,
but a hot market is a market that has a
lot of runners. And that's for me that
that's for me at least. Like for me a
small cap trader that benefits from
volatility, you have to find extension,
so
if you find in your scanner a lot of 20%
movers,
like that's for me that's that's I won't
be working that day probably.
But if you see a lot of 50%, 100%, 200%
runners, that's crazy stuff for me. And
what I'm trying to understand is
fundamentals that align my thesis. For
example, I know that 75% of small caps
die
or not die, but they they usually close
below open.
I know that
if you have, for example,
[clears throat]
if you're in the daily, if you're in a
in a stage that is a downtrend, let's
say, and you have a lot of volume, I
call it over overhead resistance. If you
have a lot of overhead resistance and
you're close to it regarding time, for
example, if the overhead resistance you
have it in 5 days ago or whatever,
for me that's very very reliable
um
criteria in order to short. Yeah. So,
technically, I have in my mind what I'm
going to do,
but fundamentals will will give me the
confidence and will align me to whatever
I'm going to do with that technical. So,
I'm having
extension, I'm having I'm understanding
the daily, which which means that if a
stock did something 2 weeks ago, will do
something similar. Maybe not the same,
but they will do something similar. So,
I I see a lot of personality of the of
the stock, let's say, regarding their
past performance.
Um and then when I when I have that
clear,
I
understand the sector that it's in.
It's very very important because if
you're in a hot sector of Bitcoin, for
example, like we did last year,
it's very very hard to short hot
sectors. Like, if you short oil and
whenever oil is going up like crazy, you
cannot short BATL, B A T L, the first
day the
the Middle East conflict starts. Like,
crazy, right? So, you have to be aware
of that.
And
once you understand like the context of
it, you will dive in on each fundamental
like as I said in a checklist. So, first
you have that watch list
and you know what you're good at. You
know that this stock you will have like,
I don't know, probably like four or five
stocks there. Yeah.
It's like, I don't know, when you were a
child, I don't know if if if you did
this,
but you put um a white paper over
a
drew a drawing that you like, I don't
know, the Smurfs or I don't know,
whatever cartoon that you you liked and
you just draw over that um
you know, over that drawing in a new
piece of paper.
And that's what I do on the stocks. Like
my drawing is my penny stock framework.
I put it below
what is happening and then my white
paper would be what's what's happening,
right? If it if it fits,
that's where I go. And obviously, that's
that's only the technical part. Wow.
fundamentals aligned,
boom, that's that's the stock that I'm
going to trade. And usually, you will
see in my P&Ls and stuff, you will see
that I make, I don't know, like
$10,000 in one stock
and I make like 250 on the other, I lose
like 400 on the other, I lose like 700
on the other and and I
earn like 300 on the other.
So,
the one that I put size in wasn't the
one that I truly believe in. The others,
maybe I'm trying to get a little bit of
cash flow to my business or whatever.
Mhm. But the one that I'm really really
locked in, that's why I say
I'm really good at picking stocks
because it's I know that I am going to
benefit from it.
I know for sure. Like I I see a
pre-market runner and I know how he's
behaving and I understand the
fundamentals and I and I say, "I'm going
to make money on this one just because
of that, just because of experience, not
because I have
I don't know a
a recipe or a magic thing." No, it's
just it it fits to what I want and I'm
going to apply it and and that's where,
you know, the
the the difficult part comes in because
you know that like
you have maybe 80% on that 80% of
success in those type of trades and it's
like two to one, for example,
>> Yeah. risk reward. So, the the difficult
part would be, "Okay, I'm going to risk
instead of 5,000, I'm going to risk
10,000." That's where the difficult part
How do you
I mean, your equity curve's beautiful
and how do you avoid
tilt? Let's say your A+ setup that you
take size on is the one that loses, but
then where you're trying to,
you know, get some cash flow, those
trades are are winning, but you have a
you have you got to
add a bunch of them. You got to pad the
wallet essentially with a bunch of these
maybe C C tier trades to catch up to
green on the day. It
Do you trade as robotic and systematic
as you said? Are there ever any times
where that the emotions creep in where
you're like, "I got to I got to make a
red to green move on the day"? Or do you
still just
Is there a point where you just shut the
computer off or you step back and say,
"Look, I can't I can't trade today after
this loss"?
My worst loss will be on tilt. Like
>> Okay. I get too stubborn on a trade that
I'm like, "I know where this is going"
and I'm totally mistaken and I
take a lot of size and it goes against
me and I stop out and then it goes
wherever I want it to go and then I try
it again and then it goes again. You
know, those are the type of trades.
Remember that I'm a very discretionary
trader and I think that's the downside
of discretionary traders. Like
systematic traders, they trust their
system so much that they they go like,
"Okay, if the if my algo, let's say, or
my system is taking this trade again, it
means that it probably is a good trade.
So,
I have to take it." Discretionary
traders,
they have that downside that
you could like you're emotionally you
could think that is a good trade again
just because you don't want to miss it.
You you get a lot of FOMO. And But it's
a mirage. Yeah,
it's very stupid to do that because
you're intelligent. On the other hand,
the good side of being a discretionary
trader is that you adapt really quick to
the markets. Systematic traders cannot
that that So So
You said the adapting, I think it's huge
and the experience. I wanted to get back
to something you said where you said
even if it tickers up like a thousand
percent, you may take the long there cuz
you know who's on the other side of it.
So, tell us a little bit about that as
far as
identifying traps, let's say.
Identifying traps. Can you identify them
to the point where it's like, "Okay,
this is an avoid stock or I should maybe
even long even though this is a at
irrational levels, I'm going to take a
trade here." And then we kind of circle
back to time frame and sizing where you
know majority of these are going to end
the day red. So, maybe this is a quick
trade. You know, tell us a little bit
bit about that as far as
Well,
like you're always as a small cap
trader, you're always going to look for
imbalances in supply and demand. And
obviously, when you have this crazy run
up of 1,000%
you will have a lot of imbalance and you
will have a lot of range, too. And I
think whenever you have this crazy
1,000% runners, you cannot size in. Like
it's that will be really stupid. But
what I want to capture in those type of
trades is range. It's not, you know,
size because if if you if you size in in
a in a stock that is,
you know, ranging I don't know, 50% for
example, if if they go from 2 to 20 and
to 20 from 20 to 15 and then 15 to 30,
like
it's very very hard to do your risk
management unless you are very very
undersized. And
those would be trades that I take for
range. Like I I would I would start like
I'm a very um
like let's say I trade around the core
and I recycle shares a lot whenever I
have that much of range as I told you
before and I trade I trade them just as
I told you. Like I have
if if it goes below, for example, VWAP,
for example, whatever. Um I know that I
cannot be no longer in that trade as a
long bias trader.
But
I know that there's a lot of difference
between the high of day and VWAP. So you
will have a lot of range. And what I do
there is try to split the trades in few
key levels so I can scale in whenever
it's it's going in my favor and I scale
out whenever it's going against me. So
that kind of technique, which is
recycling shares,
uh
is in a way it protects you from
uh you know, from a
very unusual move that would be those
moves from the high of day till VWAP
with no balance whatsoever. And usually
these kind of trades um they
they oscillate a little bit. You know,
they they bounce around uh a key level,
a key support area for example, and you
will have that opportunity to uh
de-scale on the trade whenever it went
against you. So,
right now
I
like as I have it above as a trader, I
do those kind of trades, but I also do
those kind of trades where I
hold into my core and just let it run.
You know, so I think it's a matter of
understanding if that trade that I'm
going to take really aligns with my
confidence that it will go to that level
or I'm just trying to scalp it a little
bit and and try to get this
range kind of trade. And I think
uh
if you want to scale your trading to a
eight-figure level
it's way different how you treat stocks
that if you're trading for a I don't
know a million a year
income let's say. Uh
so and and this is something that I'm
working on which is
trading for me has always been an income
generator.
Um I'm trying to get to the level that
it's uh
uh
wealth and a wealth generator. Yes,
that's correct. So, and that's what Nate
Nate has told me a lot that you're very
very good
income generator trader but you have to
go to that level where
you have to generate wealth. And that
this is where this crazy um
you know, trying to
hold into that core position what will
give you that and if you want to scale,
that's why I say that you have to be
more risk reward oriented than
how how I do it which is the high
percent winning rate
which will give you a lot of wins along
the way, but will give you few losses,
but very very harsh losses and you have
to be [clears throat]
you have to understand what kind of
trader are you.
And
like I can bear with
a lot of good days and one really hard
day because I know that my system works
that way. And I'm trying to evolve to
okay, small losses and a huge winning
day. That's that's how I trying to
evolve to that in a way. You've spoken
on recycling shares a lot too. So
entries access you're scaling in,
scaling out. You you tend to avoid
single entries like entirely almost
maybe I mean just This is a very very
like for example for me the the trades
that I that I trust the most are the
first red days for example and I can
really really hold into those because
I'm I'm very very confident. The ones
that I for example the gap and goes
which is the way I call them
that's like pretty much a pre-market
high breakout
and on those you have so much range
Yeah.
>> and it can go s-
whenever whatever that I don't usually
trust it that much and that's why I
don't I don't
hold into those positions a lot. I just
a scale into the trade and the scale
into the trade every time it goes in my
favor or against me.
You know what I hear from you which is
so inspiring is
you sound like such still an ambitious
trader
still with things to work on even after
achieving such a level of success. So,
how is your relationship with trading
you think changed now that you've hit
some of these milestones that many
traders aspire to?
It's
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> I would say that
I think being a trader is such a
is such a hard profession just because
you're never happy with it. Yeah. Yeah.
Like you're cuz what you said you were
saying those things and I don't feel at
all like I've
like obviously I have achieved more than
98.5%
of people with trading, of course. But
when you get to this 5% where where it's
normal to be profitable, like if you
surround yourself with really really big
traders and really really successful
traders,
you will find it so normal to be
profitable and you will you will find
that you're behind in so many categories
of your trading and the way you trade
that and now that I say it so,
I think it's very very important for you
guys and
the audience that is listening to me to
really be surrounded by really good
traders and traders that are where you
want to be because it it really helps.
Like I
I have a like all my friends all my
trader friends uh I would say the
majority of them are way better than me
and that's why I think I would say that
I'm the least um
successful of of all of them and
at first if you if you hear that, you
would say oh poor guy, you know, and I
feel so good because that means that I'm
surrounding myself with really really
good traders and that's
how my trading has evolved a lot. Like
being able to
surround [clears throat] yourself with
people that see this
um,
crazy profession that we're in, and you
can see the the potential that it has,
and you see it's real. Because
there's so many people out there that
that think that trading is a scam and
stuff, which
I I don't really care, but that what it
means is I have in my, you know, in
front of me the success, like really I
can touch it because they they they're
my friends and I've seen their
evolution. I've seen everything and and
and I know that it's true because I've
traded with them. And I and I know what
they do and I and a general on a on a
daily basis, I can see what they're
doing. And for example, I was talking
today with David Handlin regarding the W
and W trade, and he was 25,000 shares in
in the nines, and
it went to the 450 and he didn't cover
anything.
And when it went all the way to 830
against him,
he didn't cover.
And then when it went all the way back
to 450, he didn't cover, and he covered
at the twos,
where which was near the close where it
was his target. And I was all over the
place and the guy was so cold and so
like confidence and confidence in this
trade that I learned so much,
um, about how he handled that trade that
of course I have so much to grow and I
have so much, uh,
you know, gap between the the trader
that I want to be and the trader that I
am that
and I would say that all of them are.
Like if you talk to one of these guys
that has,
um, more than 15 million in profits,
um,
you will find that hunger in them still.
And you will find that they they their
only goal is to grow. Like they don't
care about if this is
life-changing money, they don't care if
that skill will give them, you know,
quality and and and peace of mind their
whole life.
They just want to be the best.
You know, and I think that's the key to
really be the best. I think it's to
pursue that, you know. Yeah.
I've heard it said this way, too. You
you master yourself, you master much of
the market. And that's what makes it so
fun cuz if we're the best version of
ourselves, like it it bleeds over in
real life. And I'm sure, too, I mean,
this is a question I want to ask you. I
mean, what are
habits in life that you think bleed into
trading? That
some of that discipline.
>> [clears throat]
>> You know, I think I used to think that
I I was in a phase that I was very very
disciplined regarding my my personal
life, and I was very very like, you
know, into um 75 hard. I don't know if
you've heard of that, but I I made like
three times a 75 hard, which is like the
uh
having to um
work out in a day and drinking a gallon
of water every day and reading 10 pages
of a book every single day. You know, do
that for 75 days.
And no no alcohol, like be very strict
diet and all these things, which doesn't
it doesn't
um
it's not a fitness kind of challenge,
it's a discipline kind of challenge. So,
I was very very into it.
And probably that was
one of the my best stages as a trader.
Um now,
I'm
like 40 lb overweight from those
uh times. Uh I I I play golf now cuz I
broke my Achilles.
Um and I'm in such a different stage
and I'm still like very very
in another stage of my of my trading.
And
as I'm not very very disciplined like
strict discipline in my life,
I thought that it was going to translate
to my trading a lot harder, but it's
not.
And
I think it's it's
it's a matter of how you see this game
cuz
you would think that the the discipline
in your life would translate to trading
which which I agree on,
but I've seen that the burnout comes
uh from that
mm unflexibility.
And
I was in the Traders For a Cause event
about a month ago. It was a month ago or
3 weeks ago.
And all the presentations that were with
amazing traders, they all lead to
longevity.
And for me,
that's my goal right now. Like
longevity. I I want to last the longest.
I want to I want to be trading like I've
seen a lot of traders that that they
hate day trading, for example. And they
they made a lot of money in day trading,
but they they end up hating it because
they they got into a place where
it was very very
stressful for them.
I want to have this as
you know, as as
as old as I can, I just want to be still
trading. And of course I I know that the
day trading part would be a stage of my
of my professional career. And I know
that I'm going to evolve as a swing
trader eventually, but I really want to
do that because it's the natural
consequence of my career, but not as a
burnout. So,
uh what I would say
to to to answer you or to reply to that
statement is
yes, be disciplined,
but don't be unflexible. Sometimes we're
very, very like, "Okay, I have to do
this and I have to go to the cold plunge
and I have to go to the sauna."
>> [laughter]
>> No, like
right now, for example, is I I
I live right beside the golf court and I
go and I and I'm trying to learn how to
golf and I,
you know, I go to hit some balls and I
I have my my Godson and my niece right
across the street and I ask them to go
to play tennis with me,
you know, for a couple of hours and then
go back to trading. You know, maybe the
midday
um I try to avoid it that way and I try
to get away from the markets that way
because it's healthy, because it's cool,
because it's I you know, I share with my
family and stuff,
but it's not because I, you know, want
to be in the 75 hard thing and I want to
be, you know, I don't want to translate
this discipline into trading.
Like, if you have this flexibility, you
will have more longevity on the game,
you will have less burnout, you will
have less stress.
And
yes, I'm I'm overweight right now
because I
I was so disciplined and and in one
stage, I became so undisciplined because
I didn't have that flexibility. And now
that I have flexibility, you know, I'm
I'm I'm losing weight a little by
little, step by step. I'm enjoying the
process so much. Like, I'm so much
happier than I was and I I enjoy trading
so much. Like, I
every day I trade live with my with my
team. Yeah. We're like maybe 40 people.
And I lead that group and I explain
everything that I'm doing blah blah but
I also joke a lot and I also like enjoy
and I also like, you know, I I
um you know, we talk about stuff that
are that are happening in the world and
and even I don't even watch baseball.
I'm a soccer fan like crazy and I was
talking about baseball today because
Venezuela beat Japan.
You know what I'm saying? So, it's like
I think in in the state that I am right
now is okay, I already know that I have
this skill to you know, to
don't worry about money, let's say, but
I'm more worried about longevity right
now.
>> I want to do that. longevity Going to be
doing events in nursing homes in 50
years.
>> [laughter]
>> But but I really want to get there like
not burn out and if I don't want to
trade anymore at my 70s, I don't. But I
don't want to be that guy that hates day
trading because I've seen it and Yeah. I
don't want to be that guy. You know,
I've heard this quote. You're making me
twist the words here a little bit, but
be rigid with your trading and flexible
with the lifestyle.
Mark Douglas is the person who wrote the
rules, flexible with the profit expected
expected. I was very very strict and
then Tim Sykes took me to Italy and fed
me like crazy and he told me that I
didn't gain 20 pounds, he wouldn't let
me go. So, he he was like very very
eager for me to step out from that
discipline and and I know you know what?
It It's very interesting because I I
know what he did
and
jokes aside, obviously that that was a
joke, but in at the end
if
if that discipline comes natural for
you, great. Like if you're a guy that
can work out and can, you know,
uh get at 4:00 a.m. in the morning and
go jog or whatever and and go to the
comp cold plunge and that becomes like
very very natural for you, that's great.
And
>> [clears throat]
>> wow, I wish I had that. But in my
kind of discipline, like it
doesn't fit. Like where I have three
kids. Like I cannot be
I cannot be that disciplined because if
I if I don't work out one day, I'm going
to
I can because I have I have so much
other responsibilities and I think
that's a very very important thing that
trading doesn't become your only thing.
Like I think diversification of
attention is very very important in
order to be a successful trader that I
think you you must have other things to
pursue in life than only profitability.
Well, that's an advice of someone that
has already 10 years in. But my first
three year or four, I was dive in like
crazy and I was very very intense. And I
think that intensity is very very
important to have your first years. But
then as you're aiming to longevity, I
think
you have got to have another
hobby and other uh
another
uh
area to focus your attention on. Did Did
having a family, having three kids, did
that change that like your risk
tolerance? Did it change your trading at
all?
Um
It gives you so much purpose. Yeah.
>> That
Like for example, I I I know I know
this. I've seen like every single trader
that you see that has crazy growth is
very very young. Like they usually are
all 25, 26 years old or less than 30
years old. They don't have kids. They
don't have family. And you would think
that that's because they don't have
anything to lose. But
that change like I had this hint that it
was not because of that.
Um and I met this uh
crazy trader Samsa. His
uh Yepes is is his is Twitter handle.
And he's a he's from Finland.
And he's a crazy guy. Like he is he can
go. Like he can compound. Like he made
like I don't know it was like probably
like 5 million with with 30 grand in 2
years or something like that. It was so
crazy. And he he compounded like very
very hard.
And you would think that that can only
be performed by a guy that doesn't have
any family just because, you know, risk
tolerance is equal to
uh you know, away from kids or away from
responsibilities. But this guy has two
kids.
And
and you know what the this is this is
what we were talking about regarding uh
surrounding yourself with people better
than you. And that really really took
away that
um
>> [clears throat]
>> you know, the stigma of if you have
kids, you have to be more responsible.
Of course, you have to be more
responsible in too many aspects of your
life. I can't even [clears throat] drink
and in in a night of fun because the
next morning my baby will wake me up at
at 6:00 a.m. So, of course, I have to be
more responsible in other areas of my
life. But in trading,
I think what you have to do in order to
compensate that risk tolerance, let's
say, you have to diversify your your
your income. And you have to
have your survival money uh covered. But
it doesn't
leave you off the hook in order to
really really go hard in the your
compounding and and
because if if you're a good trader and
you know that's a good setup, your job
is to size in. Like you cannot
size in in a good setup
because [clears throat] you're not doing
your job just because you have kids. I
think you have to
you have to
of course you have to
you know split that responsibilities but
you you got to do your job which is you
know grow those accounts and compound
them.
>> [clears throat]
>> I love it. I love it.
So we're got a last couple questions for
you. Once heard you reference a Tony
Robbins quote that says success without
failure success without fulfillment is a
failure.
So after achieving the success you've
had like what where do you get the that
fulfillment these days? I mean I know
you have
the stocks trading club. I mean what
what and of course the family. I mean
where do you find that level of
fulfillment these days after
Well lately I've been you know
Tim and I are building schools all over
Colombia
and that's something that is very very
like
I think
and and this is this is something that
it's it's me talking and I'm very very
open right now.
If God gave you that talent let's say or
that skill and you exploded
you got to give back in a way and I
think I found in doing the charity thing
and in the charity world
something that gives me a little bit of
more purpose because of course three
kids believe me living in the states
give me a lot of purpose
but there's something about charity that
gives me
a lot of like
I don't know how to explain it but
whenever I
give money away to build a school in
Colombia,
I
next [clears throat] day it's a really
huge setup coming in. I I don't know how
that happens, but I don't know if if I'm
too mystical, I don't know if it's just
coincidence, but I want to believe that
if you give away money to, you know, to
causes that you really really are into,
um
God just
says
God thinks that you're going to use that
money to help people and he's throwing
it away
towards you, you know, and and that
really have given me a lot a different
perspective. Um I've been going to
Colombia for the last 2 years and
seeing and and living how and and
perceiving how they live,
it's like a really perspective check and
really a reality check.
We complain too much as traders. Like I
I think we're so spoiled and I think
that we need that reality check check so
bad and we have to understand and we
have to,
you know, stop um
taking for granted what we have. That
that thing gives me a lot of like,
I don't know, strength and and
uh
you know,
I really want to trade more and be the
best just because I know that my
Locate money or whatever I spend on
Locates, yeah, that's like crazy money
for for people that are, you know,
having a lot of trouble and they it
really can change their life like that
that actually can change these lives.
And
I think that's that's that's my thing
right now. Um of course, whenever you
you step on
really slow markets and and things are
not going that well, you get like very
very like, "Oh my god, like I I I really
have to, you know, cuz I live out of
trading." Like that this is my main
source of income. So, obviously, um,
whenever things are not going well, you
go like, "Oh my god, I I won't be able
to, you know, uh, help my my people from
Colombia this month because it's
But, as I said, whenever you have this
mindset of abundance and this mindset of
hey, if you give away money, you know,
God will be good to you and he'll give
back like and you're giving back because
this talent this skill and this
opportunity that I'm We're We're making
money out of the internet and with a
laptop you can do it. And if you are
lucky enough to, you know, take
advantage of this opportunity,
I think [clears throat] you you can give
back and that's that's pretty much
that that fulfillment and I'm I'm
finding it in my family and providing
opportunities for my family in um,
building schools for for people in need
and
obviously, I'm I'm from Venezuela. I'm
I'm Latino and and I'm I'm trying to,
you know, give back to my people and my
communities. Obviously, in Venezuela, I
couldn't do it. So, it's it's about to
happen in Venezuela, but right now we're
focusing in Colombia and obviously,
like
teaching this to my people. Like that's
why I do it all in Spanish. Like my
Spanish speaking community is
is like you have so much content in
English and you have so
few people that really are into trading
in Spanish that I think that's that's my
other like baby. I think I have four
babies. I have three, actually, but this
is my fourth Yeah, yeah, which is you
know, we do events all over the place.
We we're we have gone to Buenos Aires,
Madrid, Barcelona, uh
uh Mexico, Ciudad de Mexico, uh
Medellin, you know, we have gone to so
many places doing events and stuff. What
I want to do is, you know, ending a
little bit this skepticism.
Um
people are very very skeptical in in
for trading just because there you have
so many snake oils out there to, you
know, sell you a course and blah blah
and they don't even have a um a track
record, you know, audited. Um
so, what I'm trying to do is, "Hey, this
can be done. It's a profession. It's a
skill. It's something that takes time.
It it won't give you money the third
month that you're going to, you know,
pursue it, but it will it it potentially
can give you so many things. Like
trading for me it was a life-changing
um skill and every time every day I
add up to that skill, it's more
fulfilling, it's I like it more. I I
yesterday I was in Colorado last week
and I
I traded from Colorado. It was
beautiful. All the mountains, all this
stuff and my kids like trying to learn
how to ski and blah blah. It was
beautiful. But when I got here and it
was Sunday and I was so eager to for it
to
be Monday just to trade and just to, you
know, have some some some
talk with friends about trading blah
blah that I think I found my my my
fulfillment [clears throat]
and that's something that I really
encourage you guys to pursue. Uh trading
is not a way to make money and that's
it. Trading it's a a whole thing. Like
it's a it's a career. It's a career.
It's a whole life. Yeah. Yeah. And if
you find your love it you find that
passion on on on trading, I think you
have half of the battle won.
Mhm. That's so beautiful. So well put.
So lastly, as we're wrapping up,
for the traders who are listening who
may still be in that early stage, think
your shoes, 1,900 bucks, small account,
lots of uncertainty. What's the
What advice you want to give to them?
What's the one lesson that took you the
longest to truly understand? Detach from
money. That would be my first thing.
Like detach from money. Don't ever think
about money. Just think about becoming
the best. Just think about
the the skill, developing the skill and
try to
uh take advantage of the setups. Don't
think about money. Start with really
small money because you're going to lose
the first year. Like it's very very high
probability that you're going to lose
money first year. Um try to understand
what market you like the most, what
market really um fits your personality
and what you really understand.
Find the best
audited and with track record person
that you can find on that market and try
to learn from him. Uh try to find a
community that makes you feel that
you're not alone in alone in this.
Uh prepare yourself. Study a lot. Um
understand that there's a lot of content
out there that can help you, but there's
a lot of content out there that can
really harm you. Um and that's why I
think um the track record thing, it's
very very important. I think Kim Fox
done
uh an incredible job um past years
trying to
you know, expose um
the traders out there are giving the
education. I think uh we have such a
responsibility cuz trading is not a
game. I've seen a lot of really really
awful stories and people like me that
has done it and when when I say make it
or done it or or whatever, I'm I'm
referring to being profitable. I'm not
referring to I'm not close where I am
where I want to be, but being profitable
is a very very hard thing to do and it
requires a lot of effort, a lot of
sacrifice, a lot of money, a lot of
patience, a lot of time, a lot of energy
and if you can find um
a pond that that has the traders that
you really
can learn from, I think you're in the
right track.
So Eduardo, where can the traders
listening find you?
Um my Twitter handle or my X handle
would be @edu_trades.
It's the same for Instagram.
Um
I I interact a lot in in Twitter and
Instagram. So wherever you you want to
you know, have a chat or whatever, like
just find me there and we have the
community that is called Stocks Trading
Club. It's a Spanish speaking community.
Um we're all focused in small caps. We
[clears throat] we can you know, from
now and then do a mid cap there or maybe
if if silver and oil goes crazy, also we
can do it, but um
that that's what we want to do and
if you have
a
uh in person event of trading, like go
because I think those things has given
me the most benefits that I could find
in any product that I purchase or
whatever or any coaching or any um
community or whatever, I think the in
person events has been amazing. We're
going to be
uh this year I think we're going to be
in Madrid and Buenos Aires and Miami. So
if you see us around, like come and and
and say hi and and try to get involved
with this because it's it's a very very
beautiful profession.
Well, a huge thank you EduTrades for
joining me today, sharing your story and
insights. And traders, I mean, make sure
show some love in the comments. Hit the
like button for him. And if you're
interested again in seeing EduTrades
results, they're audited on Kinfo.
Thanks again so much for coming on Chat
With Traders. It was just It was amazing
catching up with you again and just
hearing more about your journey and
adding an immense amount of value to the
trader. Thank you again.
You've reached the end of this episode
of Chat With Traders. But rest assured,
there are more episodes loaded with real
[music] market insight and zero hype on
the way soon. So, to stay updated with
each great new release, [music]
subscribe to the podcast in iTunes. And
we'd love it if you'd leave a rating and
review.
>> [music]
>> We'll catch you next time on Chat With
Traders.